<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Only the good posts</title>
    <link>https://iweb.corbin.io/site/Blog/Blog.html</link>
    <description>Here are some blog posts mirrored from my personal blog, intended to test iWeb’s blog publishing capabilities. The original posts are at blog.corbin.io.</description>
    <generator>iWeb 3.0.4</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://iweb.corbin.io/site/Blog/Blog_files/Apostrophe%20Accident.jpg</url>
      <title>Only the good posts</title>
      <link>https://iweb.corbin.io/site/Blog/Blog.html</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>The new Cupertino: a Firefox theme</title>
      <link>https://iweb.corbin.io/site/Blog/Entries/2025/8/4_The_new_Cupertino__a_Firefox_theme.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">232a8cd3-b6ce-44b5-a1c4-aa7e973c05af</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 4 Aug 2025 17:10:18 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://iweb.corbin.io/site/Blog/Entries/2025/8/4_The_new_Cupertino__a_Firefox_theme_files/tumblr_30a0a7da6c44b78cb58d97f53f9aad6d_77bfd852_1280.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iweb.corbin.io/site/Blog/Media/object027_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:165px; height:100px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Back in 2024, I released a Firefox theme that more closely matched the color and design of the macOS operating system, called Cupertino. Apple is about to release macOS Tahoe 26 with a significant redesign, so I went back to the metaphorical drawing board to help Firefox fit in again. The new Cupertino theme is &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/cupertino-theme/&quot;&gt;now available&lt;/a&gt;, and it was a lot more work than it looks!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The original theme was somewhat simple: I just used a color picker on macOS apps like Finder and Safari, and set those colors across the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/WebExtensions/manifest.json/theme&quot;&gt;theme variables that Firefox supports&lt;/a&gt;. The incoming Liquid Glass redesign of macOS 26 posed two problems: Firefox cannot replicate the translucency effects that Apple is now using everywhere, and also Liquid Glass does not look good. So many i&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/stories/macos-tahoe-the-macstories-public-beta-preview/&quot;&gt;nterface elements across the operating system&lt;/a&gt; are difficult to read, complex to understand, or both.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The main feature here is the toolbar with rounded corners and a drop shadow, which sort of matches the new floating button groups in apps like Finder, System Settings, and Safari. This was achieved with Firefox’s support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/WebExtensions/manifest.json/theme#images&quot;&gt;additional backgrounds in themes&lt;/a&gt;: the left curve is one image, the right curve is another image, and the middle section is repeated across the remainder of the screen.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I was inspired by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schillmania.com/content/entries/2006/04/more-rounded-corners/&quot;&gt;old CSS trick for creating rounded boxes&lt;/a&gt; before it was a browser-level feature, which required a background image for each corner or side of the box. Sometimes, you can’t beat the classics. Each image in this theme is in SVG format, so it looks crisp on all monitor resolutions and display scaling settings.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The background colors also don’t exactly match macOS, because Firefox applies a light filter over the toolbar for themes using a background image—it’s more obvious in &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/fireball-firefox-2/?utm_source=addons.mozilla.org&quot;&gt;photo-based&lt;/a&gt; themes. This effect can’t be turned off, so I corrected the colors the best I could and updated the rest of the theme to match the modified color values. Unlike the white-on-white interface elements seen in the new Finder and other Liquid Glass applications with minimal contrast, the Firefox window frame is a light gray and the toolbar is solid white.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Cupertino theme still supports dark mode, with colors based on Safari and Apple Music, but there’s no rounded toolbar. The light filter that Firefox applies over image backgrounds looks awful with darker backgrounds.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Firefox does allow some transparency in the search bar results, main overflow menu, and other elements, but without the fancy frosted glass-like translucency. I have this set to 97% opacity in the new Cupertino theme, because higher percentages make text more difficult to read—a problem in many applications using Liquid Glass proper.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The new theme strikes a decent balance between Apple’s updated design, features allowed by Firefox themes, and the visual contrast required for easy web browser usage. Hopefully, Firefox will eventually add native support for Liquid Glass-like effects, but I’m happy to use this in the meantime.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/cupertino-theme/&quot;&gt;install the new Cupertino theme&lt;/a&gt; from Firefox Add-ons, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/corbindavenport/cupertino&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; is on GitHub. If you want to go back to the older theme for any reason, I’ve created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/cupertino-sequoia/&quot;&gt;separate listing&lt;/a&gt; that is awaiting approval from Mozilla.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://iweb.corbin.io/site/Blog/Entries/2025/8/4_The_new_Cupertino__a_Firefox_theme_files/tumblr_30a0a7da6c44b78cb58d97f53f9aad6d_77bfd852_1280.jpg" length="54521" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My domain got hijacked through GitHub</title>
      <link>https://iweb.corbin.io/site/Blog/Entries/2025/1/11_My_domain_got_hijacked_through_GitHub.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">04961f25-bd8a-4476-af9b-482b2bf77b23</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:19:29 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>Earlier today, I got a weird email from &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.google.com/search-console/about&quot;&gt;Google Search Console&lt;/a&gt;, the service used for submitting domains and pages to Google’s search index and tracking their performance. It said that someone had been added as an owner for the subdomain test.corbin.io, which is under the corbin.io domain that I own and have registered through Google.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I didn’t add anyone as a property owner, so I decided to check the test.corbin.io domain. It loaded what seemed to be a landing page for a slot gambling website in Indonesia, with the page written in Indonesian and some Chinese in the HTML comments.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I definitely didn’t set this up, and I didn’t even remember what test.corbin.io was originally hosting. I checked my domain registrar for that domain, Hover, and the test subdomain was set as a CNAME record redirecting to corbindavenport.github.io.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I set up test.corbin.io last year to host &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.corbin.io/post/752757825366835200/how-i-made-my-new-personal-website&quot;&gt;the rewritten version of my personal website&lt;/a&gt;, before it was ready to replace my main website at corbin.io. My domain was already set up to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, the static web hosting service, so I just made a CNAME record at that subdomain and set it as &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site&quot;&gt;the custom domain for the test website’s repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here’s what I think happened. When my new website was done a few months ago, I moved it to the root domain (corbin.io) but left the test domain pointing to GitHub. Someone else set test.corbin.io as the custom directory for GitHub Pages on their repository, and since that domain was already pointing to GitHub, no setup was required on my part. I assume once I removed that custom domain from my own repository, the lock was released and GitHub allowed someone else to claim it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I’m not sure how long ago this was set up, and I probably wouldn’t have caught it if the other person didn’t try to set up as a Search Console property. As far as I can tell, none of my accounts were ever compromised, and I already had two-factor authentication enabled on both GitHub and Hover. I deleted the subdomain record in Hover and the website no longer works.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Learn from my mistake: check your domains and subdomains for possible hijacking, especially if they’re pointing to GitHub, and remove GitHub from any domain records you aren’t actively using. I have mirrored &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/corbindavenport/241f6416bc2be452e448ea69569bd2b8&quot;&gt;the website’s HTML code&lt;/a&gt; to a GitHub Gist if anyone wants to do more digging.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
