<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="AE8891B2-8A96-403D-B6AA-D723E5E90954">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20251012" date="2025-10-12 17:30:25 -0400"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;My Blog&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="4_The_new_Cupertino__a_Firefox_theme_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="313px" height="190px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Back in 2024, I released a Firefox theme that more closely matched the color and design of the macOS operating system, called Cupertino. Apple is about to release macOS Tahoe 26 with a significant redesign, so I went back to the metaphorical drawing board to help Firefox fit in again. The new Cupertino theme is &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/cupertino-theme/"&gt;now available&lt;/a&gt;, and it was a lot more work than it looks!&#xD;&#xD;The original theme was somewhat simple: I just used a color picker on macOS apps like Finder and Safari, and set those colors across the &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/WebExtensions/manifest.json/theme"&gt;theme variables that Firefox supports&lt;/a&gt;. The incoming Liquid Glass redesign of macOS 26 posed two problems: Firefox cannot replicate the translucency effects that Apple is now using everywhere, and also Liquid Glass does not look good. So many i&lt;a href="https://www.macstories.net/stories/macos-tahoe-the-macstories-public-beta-preview/"&gt;nterface elements across the operating system&lt;/a&gt; are difficult to read, complex to understand, or both.&#xD;&#xD;The main feature here is the toolbar with rounded corners and a drop shadow, which sort of matches the new floating button groups in apps like Finder, System Settings, and Safari. This was achieved with Firefox&#x2019;s support for &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/WebExtensions/manifest.json/theme#images"&gt;additional backgrounds in themes&lt;/a&gt;: the left curve is one image, the right curve is another image, and the middle section is repeated across the remainder of the screen.&#xD;&#xD;I was inspired by the &lt;a href="https://www.schillmania.com/content/entries/2006/04/more-rounded-corners/"&gt;old CSS trick for creating rounded boxes&lt;/a&gt; before it was a browser-level feature, which required a background image for each corner or side of the box. Sometimes, you can&#x2019;t beat the classics. Each image in this theme is in SVG format, so it looks crisp on all monitor resolutions and display scaling settings.&#xD;&#xD;The background colors also don&#x2019;t exactly match macOS, because Firefox applies a light filter over the toolbar for themes using a background image&#x2014;it&#x2019;s more obvious in &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/fireball-firefox-2/?utm_source=addons.mozilla.org"&gt;photo-based&lt;/a&gt; themes. This effect can&#x2019;t be turned off, so I corrected the colors the best I could and updated the rest of the theme to match the modified color values. Unlike the white-on-white interface elements seen in the new Finder and other Liquid Glass applications with minimal contrast, the Firefox window frame is a light gray and the toolbar is solid white.&#xD;&#xD;The Cupertino theme still supports dark mode, with colors based on Safari and Apple Music, but there&#x2019;s no rounded toolbar. The light filter that Firefox applies over image backgrounds looks awful with darker backgrounds.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Firefox does allow some transparency in the search bar results, main overflow menu, and other elements, but without the fancy frosted glass-like translucency. I have this set to 97% opacity in the new Cupertino theme, because higher percentages make text more difficult to read&#x2014;a problem in many applications using Liquid Glass proper.&#xD;&#xD;The new theme strikes a decent balance between Apple&#x2019;s updated design, features allowed by Firefox themes, and the visual contrast required for easy web browser usage. Hopefully, Firefox will eventually add native support for Liquid Glass-like effects, but I&#x2019;m happy to use this in the meantime.&#xD;&#xD;You can &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/cupertino-theme/"&gt;install the new Cupertino theme&lt;/a&gt; from Firefox Add-ons, and the &lt;a href="https://github.com/corbindavenport/cupertino"&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; is on GitHub. If you want to go back to the older theme for any reason, I&#x2019;ve created a &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/cupertino-sequoia/"&gt;separate listing&lt;/a&gt; that is awaiting approval from Mozilla.</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;The new Cupertino: a Firefox theme&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Monday, August 4, 2025</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
